Mike Voosen

Waxahachie, TX 75165 | 469-506-7784 | Mike. Voosen81@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mikevoosen

Objective

High performing Security Analyst with a passion for Cybersecurity. 4 years of Security experience, 14 years of overall I.T. experience, impacting positive organizational outcomes through analysis, planning, and implementation of security initiatives. Confident in ability to collaborate with cross-functional teams to solve complex, high-stakes problems. Committed to continuous improvement and contributing to team success. Currently finishing my Bachelor of Science in Cybersecurity, also pursuing certification for Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer.

Education

B.S. CYBERSECURITY | 12/2023 | SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

· Related coursework: National Cyber League | National Society of Leadership and Success | 4.0 GPA

A.A.S. COMPUTER NETWORKING | 12/2008 | ITT TECHNICAL INSTITUTE

· Graduated with 3.85 GPA

Experience

SECURITY ANALYST | JLL (JONES LANG LASALLE) | 1/2020 - PRESENT

- Manage and oversee the Web Application Firewall (WAF) (Akamai) to protect over 1300 web applications from DDoS attacks, SQLi, XSS, Remote File Inclusion, etc.
- Deployment and management of new WAF initiatives such as Site Shield, Bot Manager, and Adaptive Security Engine.
- Assisted in global deployment (65,000 sensors) of Crowdstrike XDR, then respond to detections and threats utilizing threat hunting. Threat intelligence and vulnerability research.
- Assisted with Data Loss Prevention (DLP) initiatives.
- Assist with monthly vulnerability mgmt/scanning using Qualys, and remediation of vulnerabilities.

SECURITY ANALYST | HFF (HOLIDAY FENOGLIO FOWLER) | 1/2019 – 12/2019

- Respond to Crowdstrike detections, and threat hunt based on threat intelligence
- Manage Microsoft Cloud App Security Broker (CASB) to protect Azure environment and Cloud tools.
- Monthly vulnerability scanning of severs and monthly end-point patching via SCCM

SYSTEMS SUPPORT SPECIALIST | HFF (HOLIDAY FENOGLIO FOWLER) | 2/2014 – 12/2018

- Manage Crowdstrike XDR environment, responded to detections and remediate true findings
- Monthly security patching of endpoint machines via SCCM
- Directly supported CEO, COO, President, and senior leadership
- Escalation point for Desktop technicians and Help Desk for technical issues

Skills & Abilities

Web Application Firewall (WAF) | Application Security | Python | Vulnerability Management | Crowdstrike | Data Loss Prevention (DLP) | Cloud Security | Strong Communication skills | Qualys | CASB | Security +